There are two types or styles of assessing your data.
يوجد نوعان أو طريقتان لتقييم بياناتك.
You can assess it visually and you can assess it programmatically.
يمكنك تقييمها بصريًا أو برمجيًا.
Visual assessment is just opening it and looking through the data in its entirety,
يتمثل التقييم البصري في فتح البيانات وتصفحها ككل،
in Pandas, a text editor or a spreadsheet application for example.
على سبيل المثال، محرر نصي أو تطبيق جدولي في Pandas.
This is what it looks like in Pandas for this animals.csv file,
هذا ما يبدو عليه الأمر في Pandas بالنسبة إلى ملف animals.csv،
which has three columns; animal,
الذي يحتوي على ثلاثة أعمدة؛ الحيوان
body weight in kilograms then brain weight in grams.
ووزن الجسم بالكيلو جرام ثم وزن المخ بالجرام.
This data set's pretty small,
مجموعة البيانات هذه صغيرة للغاية،
but for larger data sets Pandas will collapse rows and columns.
ولكن بالنسبة إلى مجموعات البيانات الأكبر، ستقوم Pandas بطي الصفوف والأعمدة.
So in those cases, visual assessment is best
لذا في هذه الحالات، يتم إجراء التقييم البصري على نحو أفضل
done in something like Google Sheets for example.
في شيء مثل Google Sheets على سبيل المثال.
Programmatic assessment like its name suggests,
أما التقييم البرمجي، وكما يتضح من اسمه،
is anything that uses code to view specific parts of the data,
هو أي شيء يستخدم الكود لعرض أجزاء معينة من البيانات،
like using functions or methods to summarize the data.
مثل استخدام الدوال أو الأساليب لتلخيص البيانات.
Like this dot info method for example.
مثل طريقة dot info هذه على سبيل المثال.
You can even plot the data,
يمكنك حتى رسم البيانات،
but plotting isn't done very often when wrangling.
ولكن لا يتم الرسم في كثير من الأحيان عند حدوث تعارض في البيانات.
This is more for exploring during exploratory data analysis,
ويكون الأمر أكثر أهمية للاستكشاف أثناء التحليل التوضيحي للبيانات،
which we'll get into later.
وهو ما سنتناوله لاحقًا.
Regardless of the type of assessment you're using,
وبصرف النظر عن نوع التقييم الذي تستخدمه،
assessing data can be broken down into two steps;
يمكن تقسيم تقييم البيانات إلى خطوتين؛
detecting an issue and documenting that issue.
اكتشاف مشكلة ما وتوثيق هذه المشكلة.
This process applies whether you're assessing your data visually or programmatically,
وتنطبق هذه العملية سواء كنت تقوم بتقييم بياناتك بصريًا أو برمجيًا،
which are the two types of assessment again.
وهي أنواع تقييم البيانات سالفة الذكر.
For example, we will visually assess the entirety of this data set in
على سبيل المثال، سنقوم بتقييم مجموعة البيانات هذه بالكامل بصريًا
Pandas and we detect that Gray wolf is spelt wrong, Gray woof.
في Pandas ونكتشف أن Gray wolf مكتوب بطريقة خاطئة، أي هكذاGray woof.
Then we document that issue with a bullet point.
ثم نقوم بتوثيق هذه المشكلة من خلال رمز نقطي.
I'd like to separate the issues by quality and tidiness.
أرغب في فصل المشكلات حسب الجودة والترتيب.
So Gray wolf is spelled wrong, that's our documentation.
لذا فإن Gray wolf مكتوب على نحو خاطئ، وهذا هو توثيقنا.
This is simply what we see on observation.
وهذا ببساطة ما نراه من خلال الملاحظة.
You don't have to write how to fix it which is part of
لست بحاجة إلى كتابة كيفية إصلاح المشكلة، وهو جزء من
the cleaning step in this data wrangling framework.
خطوة التنظيف في إطار عمل تعارض البيانات هذا.
So an observation would be,
لذا فإن الملاحظة ستكون،
Gray wolf is spelled wrong as opposed to something like change
أن Gray wolf مكتوب بطريقة خاطئة وبدلًا من ذلك يجب أن يتم شيء مثل تغيير
Gray woof to Gray wolf which would be more of an action item rather than an observation.
Gray woof إلى Gray wolf الذي سيكون أكثر من عنصر إجراء بدلًا من مجرد ملاحظة.